Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a lesson for you all about school.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一堂关于学校的课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to take a look at a child's report card.
今天我们要看一份孩子的成绩单。
So we're going to talk a little bit about what this means, what is a report card and
所以我们会稍微讨论一下这是什么意思，什么是成绩单，以及
also everything that's inside this report.
这份报告里的所有内容。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to learn how to describe a child's schoolwork.
所以我们要学习如何描述孩子的学业表现。
Is it good?
是好是坏？
Is it bad?
是坏是好？
So let's listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a minute to discuss the meaning
那么让我们先听一下对话，稍后我们会回来讨论这些
of some of these words and phrases.
单词和短语的含义。
Look, Jimmy's report card came today.
看，吉米的成绩单今天寄来了。
Let's have a look.
我们来看看。
What is this?
这是什么？
Where are all the grades?
成绩都在哪儿？
He's in the third grade, Sam.
他上三年级了，山姆。
You see, under each subject that he's being taught in school, he receives a mark from
你看，在学校教的每门科目下，他都会得到一个从
one to three.
一到三的评分。
A one means his achievement or work is excellent.
一分表示他的成绩或作业是优秀的。
Here in science, for example, he got a two, which means it's satisfactory.
比如在科学这门课上，他得了两分，这意味着是合格的。
What about here in physical education?
那体育课这里呢？
He got a three here, which means it's unsatisfactory.
他得了三分，这意味着是不合格的。
We should work on that with him.
我们应该在这方面帮他改进。
So confusing.
真让人困惑。
In my day, we got an A or a B if we were doing well and if we failed an exam, we would get
我那时候，如果考得好，我们会得A或B，如果考试不及格，就会得
an F. All right, we're back.
F。好了，我们回来了。
So now let's start with some language takeaway.
现在让我们开始语言要点部分。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, the first phrase here we have in language takeaway is actually a thing.
好的，语言要点里的第一个短语其实是一个东西。
It's the report card and this is the topic of today's dialogue.
就是成绩单，这也是今天对话的主题。
That's right.
没错。
Now you may remember, I'm sure pretty much it's standard everywhere in the world.
你可能还记得，我相信这在世界各地基本是标准做法。
You get a report, a small little report that tells your parents how well or how poorly
你会收到一份报告，一份小小的报告，告诉你的父母你在学校表现
you are doing in school.
是好是差。
That's right.
没错。
And then after maybe two or three months, your teacher will write down how she or he
然后大概两三个月后，你的老师会写下她或他
thinks that you're performing at school.
认为你在学校的表现如何。
That's right.
没错。
And usually parents have to sign this.
而且通常家长需要签字。
They have to say, okay, I see that my child is doing well or that he's doing poorly and
他们得说，好的，我看到我的孩子表现不错或者表现不好，
then the teacher will know as well.
这样老师也会知道。
And I think, well, you get report cards in elementary school, in high school and also
而且我觉得，嗯，你在小学、高中还有
in university, right?
大学都会收到成绩单，对吧？
You do get a report card of some sort.
你确实会收到某种形式的成绩单。
That's right.
没错。
Well, in university in America, we call them grades.
嗯，在美国的大学里，我们称之为成绩。
We don't really call them a report card.
我们一般不叫它成绩单。
In high school, middle school and elementary school, so before college, we actually have
在高中、初中和小学，也就是大学之前，我们实际上会拿到
a piece of paper and that's why it's called a card.
一张纸，所以它才叫“卡”。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
I think now for universities especially, you just go online and you see your grades.
我觉得现在尤其是大学，你直接上网就能看到成绩。
That's right.
没错。
It's on the internet.
都在网上。
But the important thing about the report card is that it tells a parent and a student what
但成绩单的重要之处在于，它告诉家长和学生他或她
his or her grades are.
的成绩是什么。
That's right.
没错。
So, grades, this is a noun, is basically your score.
所以，成绩，这是一个名词，基本上就是你的分数。
That's right.
没错。
So, maybe you took a test and you did very well on your test and you had some homework
所以，也许你参加了一次考试，考得很好，还有一些作业
and you did very well on your homework, so you have a good grade.
也完成得很好，那么你就有好成绩。
That's right.
没错。
But if you don't do your homework and you don't do well on your test, you have a bad
但如果你不做作业，考试也考不好，那你就有坏
grade.
成绩。
That's right.
没错。
So, for example, like in the United States, it's over 100 points.
所以，比如在美国，满分是100分。
So maybe a good grade would be 95 points out of 100.
所以好成绩可能是100分里的95分。
So we call that an A. That's called an A. That's right.
我们称之为A。那叫A。没错。
Or if you have a bad grade, maybe that's an F, which is 20% or 30%.
或者如果你成绩差，那可能是F，也就是20%或30%。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So now, this is where we need to make a difference between the grades that his father was looking
那么现在，这里我们需要区分一下他父亲在找的
for and then the mom says he's in the third grade.
成绩和妈妈说的他上三年级。
So it's very different between having good grades or bad grades and fifth grade or third
所以有好成绩或坏成绩与五年级或三年级
grade.
是非常不同的。
All right.
好的。
Two different grades.
两种不同的“grade”。
And we know this is confusing.
我们知道这很让人困惑。
I'm going to explain a little bit.
我来稍微解释一下。
Third grade is actually the third year of elementary school.
三年级实际上是小学的第三年。
That's right.
没错。
So in the American education system, we start in kindergarten and we have first grade, second
所以在美国教育体系中，我们从幼儿园开始，然后有一年级、二年级、
grade, third grade, all the way up until the end, which is 12th grade.
三年级，一直到最后是十二年级。
That's right.
没错。
So it's everything between when you're five years old and when you're 18 years old.
所以这涵盖了从五岁到十八岁的整个阶段。
And each year at school is a grade, a level.
在学校里，每一年就是一个年级，一个级别。
That's right.
没错。
And as you said, it's a grade in different parts of the country.
正如你所说，在美国不同地区，他们可能叫法不同。
I'm not really sure if they call them a grades or they have the same system, but basically,
我不太确定他们是否也叫年级，或者有相同的体系，但基本上，
that's what it means in English.
这就是它在英语中的意思。
You have first grade, third grade, 12th grade, finally, when you graduate.
你有一年级、三年级、十二年级，最后毕业。
That's right.
没错。
So you can say my son is in eighth grade.
所以你可以说“我儿子在上八年级”。
That's right.
没错。
It means he's in his eighth year of school.
意思是他在上学的第八年。
Right.
对。
Very good.
很好。
So that is the difference.
这就是区别。
And now, we're going to take a look at something that has to do with grades as well, is the
现在，我们来看看另一个与“grade”相关的东西，那就是
marks that you get in your test or in your report card.
你在考试或成绩单上得到的分数。
That's right.
没错。
So this might actually help.
这可能会有所帮助。
Remember when we said on your report card, your teacher might write down your grade.
还记得我们说过，在你的成绩单上，老师可能会写下你的“grade”。
That means do you have an A or a B or a C?
意思是你是得了A、B还是C？
Well, another way to call this is a mark.
嗯，另一种说法是“mark”。
So he has good marks.
所以他成绩很好。
He has good grades.
他成绩很好。
So they're basically the same thing, grades and marks.
所以它们基本上是一回事，“grades”和“marks”。
That's right.
没错。
They are.
是的。
And I know that in Britain, I think people more commonly say marks.
我知道在英国，人们更常说“marks”。
She got terrible marks at school and her father was angry with her.
她在学校成绩很差，她父亲对她很生气。
But in America, we often say, if you get good grades, I'll buy you sweets.
但在美国，我们常说“如果你成绩好，我就给你买糖果”。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So you get a prize if you get good grades usually.
所以通常你成绩好就会得到奖励。
Well, it depends on your parents.
嗯，这取决于你的父母。
On your parents.
取决于你的父母。
That's right.
没错。
Now, as we said, you can have a grade that's usually a number or a letter like A, B, C,
现在，正如我们所说，成绩通常是一个数字或一个字母，比如A、B、C、
D, F. But you can also get marks that are just very much black or white.
D、F。但你也可能得到非常黑白分明的分数。
That's satisfactory or unsatisfactory, like in this case.
就是“满意”或“不满意”，就像这种情况。
That's right.
没错。
So satisfactory, this is an adjective, it describes something, is a good thing.
所以“satisfactory”是一个形容词，描述某件事，是好事。
So how did he do?
那他表现如何？
Well, his performance was satisfactory.
嗯，他的表现令人满意。
It's okay.
还行。
But if it's bad or if it's not good, we call it unsatisfactory.
但如果不好或不行，我们就叫它“unsatisfactory”。
That's right.
没错。
So this doesn't really have a number, as you can tell.
所以这没有具体的数字，你可以看出来。
It's just basically pass or fail.
基本上就是及格或不及格。
That's about it.
就这样。
Good or bad.
好或坏。
That's it.
就是这样。
Exactly.
没错。
No grade.
没有具体分数。
And we'll explain this in a minute.
我们一会儿会解释这个。
There are some classes where you can't have a grade like an A or a B. And that's why we
有些课程你不能给A或B这样的分数。这就是为什么我们
have this satisfactory, unsatisfactory.
有“满意”和“不满意”这种评分。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a lot of language there.
我们已经看了很多语言点。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again?
我们为什么不把对话再听一遍呢？
Look, Jimmy's report card came today.
看，吉米的成绩单今天寄来了。
Let's have a look.
我们来看看。
What is this?
这是什么？
Where are all the grades?
分数都在哪里？
He's in the third grade, Sam.
他上三年级，山姆。
You see, under each subject that he's being taught in school, he receives a mark from
你看，他在学校学的每个科目下面，他都会得到一个从
one to three.
一到三的分数。
A one means his achievement or work is excellent.
一分表示他的成绩或作业非常优秀。
Here in science, for example, he got a two, which means it's satisfactory.
比如在科学这里，他得了两分，这意味着令人满意。
What about here in physical education?
那体育这里呢？
He got a three here, which means it's unsatisfactory.
他在这里得了三分，这意味着不满意。
We should work on that with him.
我们应该在这方面帮他改进。
So confusing.
真让人困惑。
In my day, we got an A or a B if we were doing well, and if we failed an exam, we would get
在我那时候，如果表现好，我们会得A或B，如果考试不及格，我们会得
an F.
F。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看“流利度构建器”里的一些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
You could have said, let's have a look, Marco.
你本可以说“让我们看看”，马可。
That's one of the key phrases in today's dialogue.
这是今天对话中的关键短语之一。
That's right.
没错。
He, the dad, got the report card and he said, all right, let's have a look.
他，那位爸爸，拿到了成绩单，然后说：“好的，让我们看看。”
All right, this is a very common way to say, let's see, or let me look at that.
“好的”是一种很常见的说法，意思是“让我们看看”或“让我看看那个”。
So let's have a look.
所以“让我们看看”。
Maybe it's just one person, me, but we still say this, let, let us.
可能只有我一个人，但我们还是这么说，“让，让我们”。
So it's plural.
所以它是复数形式。
It's very weird, but it just means let me look, let me see.
这很奇怪，但它只是意味着“让我看看，让我瞧瞧”。
And exactly.
正是这样。
As you said, even though it's in plural and you may be by yourself or only you are going
就像你说的，尽管它是复数形式，而且你可能是一个人或者只有你要看某样东西，
to look at something, people still say, let's have a look.
人们仍然会说“让我们看看”。
Let's have a look here.
让我们看看这里。
It means I want to look at this, so if I say, Hey, I just bought this new CD.
它的意思是“我想看看这个”，所以如果我说：“嘿，我刚买了这张新CD。”
Okay.
好的。
I can say, Hey, let's have a look.
我可以说：“嘿，让我们看看。”
All right.
好的。
And I could give it to Marco and he can look at the case and see who the musician is.
我可以把它交给马可，让他看看这个案子，找出那位音乐家是谁。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Now talking about one of the subjects in school, that means some of the classes that you have,
现在说到学校里的一个科目，也就是你上的一些课，
we had science, we have history, and there's another one called physical education.
我们有科学课、历史课，还有一门叫体育课。
All right.
好的。
So this is a class that has many different names.
所以这门课有很多不同的名称。
It's physical, so you know that it has to do with your body.
它是“体育”的，所以你知道它和你的身体有关。
So basically it's sports class and you play sports like football, basketball, things like
基本上就是体育课，你踢足球、打篮球之类的运动，
that.
等等。
It's also called PE.
它也叫PE。
PE for short.
PE是简称。
Yeah.
是的。
Because remember physical in English starts with a P, PH, physical.
因为记住，“体育”在英语里以P开头，PH，physical。
But this is what I was saying earlier, Marco, you can't give a person an A or a B in physical
但这就是我之前说的，马可，你不能在体育课上给学生打A或B。
education.
体育课。
Well, you don't really.
嗯，你确实不会。
So normally students get satisfactory or unsatisfactory.
所以通常学生得到的是“合格”或“不合格”。
Because usually it doesn't mean that you have to be very good at sports.
因为通常这并不意味着你必须非常擅长运动。
Sometimes it's just the effort counts.
有时候努力本身就是一种肯定。
You may not be very good at soccer or football or basketball, but if you try really hard,
你可能不擅长足球、橄榄球或篮球，但如果你真的很努力，
you're running around and you're actually doing what you're supposed to be doing, then
你跑来跑去，确实在做你该做的事，那么
you get a satisfactory note.
你就能得到一个满意的评价。
It means, yeah, I mean, you're not the best player in the world, but you're doing what
意思是，没错，你虽然不是世界上最好的球员，但你在做
you're supposed to.
你该做的事。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So now when the father was talking, he's like, oh, you know, I don't understand this report
所以刚才那位父亲在说话时，他说，哦，你知道，我不懂这份成绩单，
card in my day, we got an A or a B.
我那个年代，我们拿的是A或B。
All right.
好的。
So this is a common phrase that people say when they want to talk about when they were
所以这是人们想谈论自己
children or when they were growing up.
小时候或成长时期时常用的一句话。
So older people often say, oh, in my day, things were different.
所以年长的人常说，哦，我那个年代，情况不一样。
So this is a way to make a comparison between now and the past.
这是一种比较现在和过去的方式。
Yeah, right.
是啊，没错。
So you're basically saying when I was a child or many years ago, this was what happened
所以你基本上是在说，我小时候或很多年前，事情是这样的
or this is how it used to be.
或者过去是那样的。
In my day, school was much more difficult.
我那个年代，学校要难得多。
Today, it's very, very easy.
今天呢，非常非常容易。
That's right.
没错。
So this is how you start this comparison between the time when you were a child to now.
所以这就是你开始比较自己小时候和现在的方式。
Yes.
是的。
In my day.
在我那个年代。
All right.
好的。
And to finish off, we're going to talk about failing an exam because obviously sometimes
最后，我们要谈谈考试不及格，因为显然有时候
you do fail.
你确实会不及格。
Yeah.
嗯。
So when you fail, fail an exam, you get a very bad grade, an F.
所以当你不及格，考试没通过时，你会得到一个很差的成绩，F。
An F.
F。
So F for fail.
所以F代表不及格。
It's easy to remember.
这很好记。
That's right.
没错。
So you say, you can say I didn't pass the exam, but you can also say I failed the exam.
所以你可以说“我没通过考试”，但也可以说“我考试不及格”。
Yes.
是的。
And normally fail means you received less than 60%.
通常不及格意味着你得分低于60%。
That's right.
没错。
Or 50%.
或者50%。
So it's, yeah, 50%.
所以是，嗯，50%。
So basically you missed, if there are 10 questions on the exam, you missed five or six or seven
所以基本上你错过了，如果考试有10道题，你错了五道、六道或七道。
or all the way to 10 of them.
或者一直到十个。
So you missed more than half of the questions.
所以你答错了超过一半的问题。
That's right.
没错。
And it's not only for school.
而且这不只适用于学校。
For example, your driver's exam, when you're going to get your driver's license, you can
比如说，你的驾照考试，当你去考驾照的时候，你可以
also pass or fail that exam.
通过或没通过那次考试。
And if you fail the exam, you have to take it again.
如果你没通过考试，就得重考。
That's right.
没错。
So that's all the fluency builder words we have for you today.
以上就是我们今天为你准备的所有流利度构建词汇。
Let's take a look at them again and we'll be right back.
让我们再看一遍，我们马上回来。
Look, Jimmy's report card came today.
看，吉米的成绩单今天寄来了。
Let's have a look.
我们来看看。
What is this?
这是什么？
Where are all the grades?
成绩都去哪儿了？
He's in the third grade, Sam.
他上三年级了，山姆。
You see, under each subject that he's being taught in school, he receives a mark from
你看，他在学校学的每个科目下面，都会得到一个从
one to three.
一到三的分数。
A one means his achievement or work is excellent.
一分表示他的成绩或作业很优秀。
Here in science, for example, he got a two, which means it's satisfactory.
比如在科学这门课上，他得了两分，这意味着成绩合格。
What about here in physical education?
那体育课这里呢？
He got a three here, which means it's unsatisfactory.
他得了三分，这意味着不合格。
We should work on that with him.
我们应该在这方面多帮帮他。
So confusing.
真让人困惑。
In my day, we got an A or a B if we were doing well.
我那时候，如果学得好，我们会得A或B。
And if we failed an exam, we would get an F.
如果考试没通过，就会得F。
All right.
好吧。
So big question, Marco.
那么，关键问题来了，马可。
When you were a student, did you get good grades?
你当学生的时候，成绩好吗？
I got good grades, but not great grades.
我成绩不错，但不算特别好。
I was always the type of student that paid attention in class, did my homework, but never
我从来都是那种上课认真听讲、做作业，但从不
studied.
复习的学生。
Ah, so you did not study for the tests.
啊，所以你考试前不复习。
No, but that's why I never got an A, for example, or an A plus.
对，但这就是为什么我从来没得过A，比如A或A+。
But I always got a B. So I was that type of just more chilled type of student.
但我总是得B。所以我就是那种比较放松的学生。
You like to be in the middle.
你喜欢居中。
Yeah.
是的。
Well, this was the thing.
嗯，事情是这样的。
I didn't like to pay attention in class, so that was different because I would pay attention,
我不喜欢在课堂上专心听讲，所以那不一样，因为我会注意听，
I would take some notes, but then I would just remember everything.
我会记一些笔记，然后就能记住所有东西。
So I did all right for the exam.
所以考试我考得还行。
I didn't really have to study.
我真的不需要复习。
But sometimes in other subjects I did, I really liked them.
但有时候在其他科目上，我确实喜欢它们。
So it wasn't studying.
所以那不算复习。
It was more fun for me.
对我来说更像是乐趣。
So then I would get great grades.
所以那时我会取得好成绩。
What about you?
你呢？
I always studied for tests.
我总是为考试复习。
Generally my grades were pretty good.
总的来说，我的成绩相当不错。
Now something that we didn't talk about here is a GPA.
现在我们没谈到的一个东西是GPA。
This is something that is very popular in the United States.
这在美国非常流行。
Basically even if you want to apply for schools, your GPA is what counts.
基本上，即使你想申请学校，GPA才是关键。
What is a GPA?
什么是GPA？
That's right.
没错。
Well, we don't really have a GPA until high school, and then it's in high school and college.
嗯，我们直到高中才有GPA，然后是在高中和大学里。
And GPA stands for G-Grade P-Point A-Average.
GPA代表G-成绩 P-点 A-平均。
So grade point average.
所以是平均绩点。
That means we take all of our marks or all of our grades together.
这意味着我们把所有分数或成绩加在一起。
So science grade, English grade, history grade, and we make an average.
比如科学成绩、英语成绩、历史成绩，然后算出一个平均值。
So if I get mostly A's, my GPA is 4.0.
所以如果我大部分得A，我的GPA就是4.0。
If I get mostly B's, my GPA is 3.0.
如果我大部分得B，我的GPA就是3.0。
And then it goes lower and lower.
然后它会越来越低。
And if you have a really bad GPA, like a 1, you probably won't finish high school.
如果你的GPA很差，比如1分，你可能毕不了业。
Now the GPA is very important for many reasons.
现在GPA非常重要，原因有很多。
First of all, because it's also kind of a summary of your application to universities,
首先，因为它也是你大学申请的一个总结，
right?
对吧？
They take a look at your GPA.
他们会看你的GPA。
Absolutely.
当然。
So this is a way to say, okay, how is this student overall?
所以这是一种方式，用来判断，好吧，这个学生整体怎么样？
How is this student in all of her classes, not just one class?
这个学生所有课程的表现如何，而不仅仅是一门课？
Right.
对。
And then they see if you have a 3.5, they say, oh, well, it's pretty good.
然后如果他们看到你有3.5，他们会说，哦，还不错。
Yeah, 3.5 is good.
是的，3.5算不错。
4 is the best.
4分是最好的。
And again, a 3 is good, it's okay.
再说一次，3分算好，还可以。
But a 2 or a 1 is not very good.
但2分或1分就不太好了。
That's right.
没错。
So it's very interesting because all around the world, they have different grading systems.
所以这很有趣，因为世界各地有不同的评分系统。
I think I would say that the United States is the only place where I've seen that they
我想我会说，美国是我唯一见过使用
use the A, B, C, D, F system.
A、B、C、D、F系统的地方。
In Latin American countries, for example, they don't do it over 100, they do it over
例如，在拉丁美洲国家，他们不是按100分制，而是按
10.
10分。
So you would get a grade over 10.
所以你会得到一个超过10分的成绩。
Or in some countries, over 20.
或者在一些国家，超过20分。
I've seen that as well.
我也见过这种情况。
In Italy, it's not.
在意大利，不是这样。
It's over 20.
是超过20分。
So you would get a 14, I think, would be a passing grade over 20.
所以你会得到14分，我想，那是20分制中的及格分。
Well, let us know, listeners, if you have a different grading system in your country.
嗯，听众们，如果你们国家有不同的评分系统，请告诉我们。
Also, you can let us know how were your grades when you're studying in school.
另外，你也可以告诉我们你在学校学习时的成绩怎么样。
You don't have to tell us, but we'd like to talk to you about grades.
你不必非得告诉我们，但我们很想和你聊聊成绩的事。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye.
再见。
This is Inner Circle, signing off.
这里是Inner Circle，节目结束。